<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wrighting April</title><link href="http://wrightaprilm.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://wrightaprilm.github.io/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://wrightaprilm.github.io/</id><updated>2014-05-15T11:06:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>About Me</title><link href="http://wrightaprilm.github.io/posts/about_me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-15T11:06:00-05:00</updated><author><name>April Wright</name></author><id>tag:wrightaprilm.github.io,2014-05-15:posts/about_me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;April Wright&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Graduate student: David Hillis' Lab at the University of Texas at Austin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-mail contact: wright [dot] aprilm [at] utexas.edu &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google chat or Docs: wright [dot] aprilm [at] gmail.com &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office: Patterson Labs 129&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Research Interests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fossils and Phylogeny&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm very interested in the best practices for estimating phylogenetic trees from the fossil record. Fossil data presents many challenges for researchers investigating phylogenetic and macroevolutionary questions. Missing data, biases in preservation and model adequacy are all topics in which I have an interest. Keep an eye on my blog for tutorials and other hosted materials on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Putting Fossils in Trees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we best make use of fossil data when estimating divergence dates? How can current methods, such as 'tip-dating' methods, be applied to paleontological information? Along with collaborators, I am developing empirical projects to address this question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Relevant output:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with two collaborators, I am hosting a &lt;a href="http://vertpaleo.org/Annual-Meeting/Workshops.aspx"&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://vertpaleo.org/Annual-Meeting/Symposia.aspx"&gt;symposium&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href="http://vertpaleo.org/Annual-Meeting/Home.aspx"&gt;SVP meetings&lt;/a&gt;. Join us if you happen to be in Berlin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Estimation and Use of Phylogenetic Trees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can put a tree on it, I'm interested. I'm a part of several projects in the Hillis lab, including understanding the True Bug phylogenetic tree and examining the contribution of topological uncertainty in modeling the evolution of complex traits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Relevant paper:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.biomedcentral.com/1471-2148/14/99/abstract"&gt;Long-branch attraction and the phylogeny of true water bugs (Hemiptera: Nepomorpha) as estimated from mitochondrial genomes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computational literacy and Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm probably most vocally interested in the pedagogy of computer science and increasing the participation of underrepresented groups in this field. My courses taught page is frequently updated with course materials, all of which are CC-BY. Feel free to use these materials as you see fit (but attribute me!), or get in touch with me to talk more about them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Courses Taught</title><link href="http://wrightaprilm.github.io/posts/courses_taught.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-15T11:06:00-05:00</updated><author><name>April Wright</name></author><id>tag:wrightaprilm.github.io,2014-05-15:posts/courses_taught.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Keep an eye here for links to my courses taught&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the course materials for the Spring 2014 Biocomputing Working Group 
(co-taught with Ben Liebeskind) &lt;a href="https://github.com/wrightaprilm/BioComputing2014"&gt;on my&lt;/a&gt;Github page.
You can find course materials for the SSC python short course &lt;a href="../CourseMaterials.zip"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the post-course wrap up &lt;a href="http://wrightaprilm.github.io/posts/ssc-wrap.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
Course materials for the four-day Big Data in Biology summer school are &lt;a href="https://github.com/wrightaprilm/ccbb_pythonspring2014"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>